Contact

nursekiz@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/roxaneevans-moore-msn-rt-clc-a60138b7 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Communication
Analytical Skills
Passionate about work

Languages

English

Certifications

BLS
NRP
Certified Lactation Consultant
S.T.A.B.L.E.S

Roxane Evans-Moore MSN, RT, CLC

Family Nurse Practitioner Student

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

I am striving for a position in nursing where I can use my experience and knowledge of nursing practices. My years of experience as a nurse in diverse areas of nursing and knowledge as a respiratory therapist and respiratory care manager in neonatal, pediatrics, and adult critical care areas has provide me with great benefits in healthcare.

Experience

Memorial Hermann Health System NICU Registered Nurse February 2011 - Present (9 years 6 months) Houston, Texas Area

Family Nurse Practitioner Student

Clear Lake Regional Hospital Neonatal Intensive Care Nurse May 2008 - January 2011 (2 years 9 months) Webster, Tx

Provide care to infants admitted to the NICU. Assisted physicians and NNPs with bedside procedures and surgeries. Provided care to infants receiving supplemental oxygen via the nasal cannula, oxyhoods, and nasal CPAP. Administered medications, antibiotics, blood and blood products to infants. Started and maintained PIV sites.

- Primary care, assessment and evaluation of neonatal patients.
- Charge nurse on neonatal floor. Oversaw average of number patients per shift.
- Supervised and managed nurses and clinical support staff in patient care activities while maintaining a high level of staff morale and professionalism.
- Self-directed with good judgment skills. High level of personal accountability.
- Educated parents on prior discharge and neonatal CPR.

- Demonstrated ability to guide and motivate outstanding healthcare members.
- Ensured HIPPA compliance.
- · Delegated staff nurse duties.
- Trained new staff on quality control procedures.
- Strong leader for nursing personnel assigned to the unit.

Children's Hospital of New Orleans (Travel Nurse) NICU Nurse

December 2007 - March 2008 (4 months)

New Orleans, Louisiana

- Primary care, assessment and evaluation of neonatal patients.
- Performed lab tests and communicated results.
- Instructed infant's family on proper discharge care.
- Followed infection control procedures.
- Assisted physicians with bedside surgeries and procedures.

West Jefferson Hospital (Travel NICU Nurse)

NICU Nurse

September 2007 - November 2007 (3 months)

Metarire, Louisiana

Provided care for infants both in Level III & II NICU. Provided care for infants born prematurely, born with infant birth defects and anomalies, as well as pre and post- surgical patients. Provided care for ventilated and non-ventilated infants. Assisted physicians with bedside procedures and surgeries. Educated families on the care of infants prior to discharge.

Touro Infirmary Hospital (Travel Nurse)

NICU Nurse

August 2006 - August 2007 (1 year 1 month)

New Orleans, Louisiana

Travel NICU Nurse- Level III, II, Step-down, and Newborn Nursery
Provided care for infants in the NICU and Newborn Nursery. Provided care
for ventilated and Non-ventilated patients. Started and maintained PUV
sites. Provided care to infants with PICC lines, UVC's, UAC's and Art-lines.
Administered medications, antibiotics, immunizations, blood, and blood
products to infants. Educated parents throughout hospital stay and care of
infant prior to discharge.

Twelve Oaks Medical Center NICU/Nursery Nurse November 2005 - August 2006 (10 months) Houston, Texas

Staff Nurse- NICU Level II, I, Newborn Nursery, and Transitional Nursery. Attended all deliveries both natural and Cesarean deliveries. Provided care to infants immediately after birth either in the birthing room or the OR. Provided transitional or resuscitative to infants after birth if needed. Obtained lab and blood cultures. Administered medications, antibiotics, and immunizations. Started and maintained PIV sites infusing TPN and lipids or clear fluids. Provided care to critical or ventilated infants prior to transport to other facilities.

Memorial Medical Center Labor and Delivery Nurse May 2005 - August 2005 (4 months) New Orleans, Louisiana

Staff Nurse Labor & Delivery

Provided care to women in pre-term and termed labor. Provided care to preterm women with conditions such as hypertension, diabetes, pre-eclampsia, gestational diabetes, asthma, sickle cell anemia, and other medical conditions. Started and maintained PIV sites. Administered medications, antibiotics, and transfused bold to patients. Prep patients for C-section deliveries, served as a circulator in the OR during C-Section maintain a safe OR and assisting NNP with infant care. Provided care to mothers post-op in recovery area after delivery. Education patients

Ochsner Clinical Foundation Hospital Transplant Nurse August 2004 - May 2005 (10 months)

New Orleans, Louisiana

Provided care to pre and post- transplant patients. Provided care for dialysis patients and gastric-bypass patients. Started and maintained PIV sites. Provided care and maintained central lines.

- Chronic patient care on transplant unit, adeptly handling all aspects of treatment from medication to monitoring for number patients per shift.
- Effective counseling in health maintenance and disease management.
- Performed lab tests and communicated results.
- Liaised between patients and physicians to ensure patient comprehension of treatment plans.

Followed infection control procedures.

Ochsner Clinic Foundation
NICU Nurse
February 2001 - July 2004 (3 years 6 months)

New Orleans, Louisiana

Staff Nurse- NICU Level III, II, and Step-down Unit, and Floated to PICU Charge Nurse

Mentor & Preceptor

- Primary care, assessment and evaluation of neonatal and pediatric patients.
- Led training program and conducted classes for nurses on the unit.
- Charge nurse on neonatal unit. Supervised average of number patients per shift.
- Effectively supervised number nurse in the unit.
- Self-directed with astute judgment skills. High level of personal accountability.
- · Trained new staff.
- Followed infection control procedures.
- Strong leader for nursing personnel assigned to the unit

Ochsner Clinical Foundation

7 years 6 months

Resiratory Care Manager August 1999 - January 2001 (1 year 6 months) New Orleans, Louisiana

Respiratory Care Manager

(Med surgical area, Adult ICU, Cardiac Care Unit, Heart transplant Unit, ED, PACU, PICU and NICU).

Served as a resource person to other health care disciplines and respiratory care staff. Coordinated activities and schedules of respiratory staff in all areas of the respiratory. Attend all critical deliveries. Attend all code blues throughout the hospital. Set up nitric tank in the operating rooms for surgery. Supervised staff through effective human resources management. Advised the task concerning technical task and assisted with duties as needs arise. Documented and conducted performance evaluations for staff members. Communicated and implemented departmental policies and procedures as directed.

- Effectively supervised RT's. Improved annual employee retention rate from number to number percent.
- Ensured HIPAA compliance.

- Processed monthly reports for departmental performance.
- Coordinated Quality Improvement Activities (QIA's) to identify performance areas for improvement.
- Participated in unit-based Quality Assurance Program.
- Developed and produced all office flyer notifications for important policy changes, department and hospital news and events.

Registered Respiratory Therapist

August 1993 - August 1999 (6 years 1 month)

New Orleans, louisiana

Respiratory Care Therapist

Respiratory Lead Therapist

Preceptor

(ICU, HTU, CCU, PACU, and ED units)

Monitored, managed and weaned patient's oxygen and/or mechanical ventilation. Performed ventilator checks according to hospital policy and procedures. Display insight to patient's clinical condition via comments recorded in therapist notes. Weaned/maintained patient parameters established by the physicians. Coordinated care with the patient's nurse to provide optimal rest and care to the patient. Attend and respond to all blue code in adult areas.

Education

University of phoenix

Master's degree, Family Practice Nurse/Nursing · (2018 - 2021)

University of Phoenix

Master's Degree, Registered Nursing, Nursing Administration, Nursing Research and Clinical Nursing · (2011 - 2014)

Dillard University

Bachelor's Degree, Nursing · (1996 - 2000)

Our Lady of Holy Cross College

Bachelor's Degree, Respiratory Care Therapy/Therapist · (1990 - 1993)

Xavier University of Louisiana

Bachelor's Degree, Biology/Biological Sciences, General · (1981 - 1988)